<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>http://fabian-gosebrink.com</title>
   
   <link>http://offering.solutions</link>
   <description>Articles about Angular & ASP.NET</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Fabian Gosebrink</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Lessons I learnt from organising a conference</title>
	  <link>//blog/articles/2017/07/18/things-i-learned-from-organising-a-conference/</link>
	  <author>Fabian Gosebrink</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-18T19:55:00+02:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blog/articles/2017/07/18/things-i-learned-from-organising-a-conference/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It has been quiet here for a while… :-)</p>

<p>You may have noticed that I organised my first conference <a href="http://dotnetday.ch/">.NET Day</a> about two months ago. Well, that is not true. The organisation itself took place long before that but the event took place approximately two months ago. With this distance of time I want to gather up what I learned from organising this event, what I take with me and what will influence the next conference if I will do this again some time :-)</p>

<p>I needed some time to really figure out all the thoughts &amp; things which were going on and break them down to the following points. If you made similar experiences or want to add new ones feel free to comment :)</p>

<h2 id="be-prepared-and-have-a-plan-b">Be prepared and have a plan B</h2>

<p>On the event you are planning, things will happen you never thought of. This can be good or bad things, but you will <em>not</em> be prepared of them. So what you can do is starting early (!) and thinking of any possible situation which may happen. (You can’t, but more on this later :-) This can be that a speaker is not coming because the night before he got sick or something, a microphone does not work, the food can not be served etc. You should always think of those things and play with that thought in your head. “What am I doing if xyz happens?” is the question you have to ask for youself. Have backup speakers. Have saved the telephone numbers of all pizza delivery services in your area to be prepared if food can not be served. Have a car there which you can use to get something which you not have thought of etc. If you re-think your event over and over again you will possibly come to a point where you can say to yourself that you are prepared for every single thing which can happen. (Which you can’t, but you did your best here :)</p>

<p>So make that a little easier and taking this thought of being prepared further we can take a look at the next point…</p>

<h2 id="change-the-perspective-to-an-attendee">Change the perspective to an attendee</h2>

<p>…changing the perspective to an attendee. Image you are walking into the venue, what do you expect? Getting your ticket scanned? Getting a lanyard? Seeing the organiser? Just think of where do you would like to sit, what would be cool in the breakes? Is there something you would say “If there would be xyz, that’d be cool!”. If you attended to other conferences before and you can clone some ideas: Cool! If you were missing something on other conference: Try to add it to our conference. Its your attendees who give feedback &amp; do tweet about it. So you have to do everything they feel comfortable. From the selection of talks, topics over the venue, how you treat them etc.</p>

<h2 id="ask-for-help">Ask for help</h2>

<p>You noticed something, didn’t you? Thats massive work. Well until here we did not organise anything so far. All that were thoughts! But you need another input. Ask your friends, your family if idea xyz is cool. “Would you like it if …?”, “What do you think of xyz?”. Also tell them if you arranged something. Not to get compliments on how good you are but to trigger their thouoghts a bit. “Hey I have just organised thisandthat” - “Cool, but did you think of thatandthis, too then?” - Boom! You got your input.</p>

<p>Further ask a friend to help you out. There are so much things to do which are completely separated and can be done by another one. If you organise a conference at some point you have to …</p>

<h2 id="talk-to-each-other-and-delegate">Talk to each other and delegate</h2>

<p>… delegate! We took OneNote for that which was completely fine. Just to keep each other up to date, if the emails to the speakers were sent out, which speaker said yes/no/maybe. Which topic by whom, which sponsors do we have, mail proposals for review etc. Delegate something, divide the work by two or more and give exact advises. “Can you please write a draft mail for the sponsors to do this and that”. Maybe you can organise via SCRUM or Kanban. Feel free to do that as you want, but split up the work. It is getting easier then.</p>

<h2 id="dont-do-a-talk-when-you-organise-the-conference">Don’t do a talk when you organise the conference</h2>

<p>I did that mistake. I really thought a long time about “Shall I speak or not?”. In the end I thought my topics were interesting and so I spoke at the event I organised. This was a mistake if I look back. And the reason for that was that I was not focussing on my talk. You are so distracted by anything what is going on that you can not focus on your talk. I did not get into this tunnel completely giving everything I have in this 45 minutes. (I even thought about so much things the night before the event, that I forgot that I only had 45 minutes and practices for 60 instead!!!) I only have been at the talk at like 70% or something. And it went bad. I forgot to show demos, forgot a cable to show something with my mobile phone, my timing was bad, I moved the slides too fast etc.</p>

<p>So stay focused. Either on talking or on doing the things around it…but for me both is not working.</p>

<h2 id="start-early">Start early</h2>

<p>With all the things in mind: You can not start too early with that. Even if other people youre talking to tell you “We still have time”: Try to organise everything sooner than later. If you just ask people about their opinion maybe you notice things you haven’t thought of. And these are things you have to organise. So start early with you preparations. Maybe there is no “Too early” at all :-)</p>

<h2 id="during-the-conference-observe--listen-">During the conference: Observe &amp; Listen !!!</h2>

<p>Maybe this is the most important point. Listen to feedback. It won’t go perfect the first time you organise a conference and people will tell you. And that is okay. Take it as a chance to get better. How was the food? How was the venue? Take a look at the attendees during the talks and during the brakes. Do not only talk with people you know. Ask them about one thing specifically. “How do you like …?”, “Are you satisfied with …”, “Is it okay that thingandthat is like …”. In addition to that provide a possibility for feedback. We used google forms for that. We always asked about ratings and if the rating was not the best there was the possibility to add “Why is it not rated with 5 stars? What can we do better next time?” and we got great feedback!</p>

<h2 id="enjoy-the-moment">Enjoy the moment</h2>

<p>Last but not least: Enjoy the moment. I was sitting in the conference very excited and tried to have everything under control as a friend and attendee said “Don’t worry. It will work. Lean back and enjoy the conference”. When I look back now that was one of the greatest advices that day.</p>

<p>Thank you and once again thanks to all attendees. You made this day very special and I had a great birthday that day :-)</p>

<p>BR</p>

<p>Fabian</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Announcing the .NET Day 2017</title>
	  <link>//blog/articles/2017/04/02/announcing-the-dotnetday-2017/</link>
	  <author>Fabian Gosebrink</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-04-02T19:12:00+02:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blog/articles/2017/04/02/announcing-the-dotnetday-2017/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I am very happy to announce the .NET Day 2017 in Switzerland! In this blogpost I want to give you a small background information on this, how this idea came up and about the current status.</p>

<h3 id="the-beginning">The beginning</h3>

<p>The idea of this conference day came into my mind in the middle of 2016. I love conferences. I think that a developer has to stay updated on his well known topics as well as be open to new topics and has to keep on learning over and over again. If he wants to stay open and focused on the same time he has to take a look whats new, what is established and learn from others. If you listen to a talk on a conference, on a usergroup or whereever: You get an idea of if you are interested in this topic or not. You see if you want to dig deeper or not. In a very short amount of time. And if you already know: you can see whats new, other perspectives and so on. This is worth a lot.</p>

<p>In addition to that Microsoft came up with a lot of new stuff during the last time. And I think beside the awesome TechDays in Switzerland there should be another paltform to spread this knowledge. But I did not want to make a commercial conference. This thing should be community driven. The focus is on spreading knowledge. The new stuff.</p>

<p>After a few thoughts and conversations the idea grew and I fixed a name and a date and I could go ahead organising speakers.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>To mention this: I never organsied a conference before. I had no idea what to be done, no idea how to start with that thing. But Microsoft helped me a lot with this. They offered the room and helped me where they could as well as forcing me to take care about stuff with “Do it as you like”.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After a while I realized that I could not do this on my own. So I asked my friend Manuel Meyer for help. He immediately said yes and there we are:</p>

<h3 id="how-it-grew">How it grew</h3>

<p>Through a great community and platforms like papercall.io we started a call for paper to get the speakers and the talks. IMHO we got a great agenda and speakers now (which I am not telling because I am part of it. I really do not count myself to the top speakers we have there. I am more than proud to be in between this international known names to who every single one I am looking up to).</p>

<p>After a while we got the agenda fixed and also Manuels and my shared OneNote grew and grew ;-).</p>

<p>We walked further and organsied sponsors. Some emails went out never getting any response back. But some of them came back loving the idea and they wanted to support us with the bigger one of the sponsoring packages. Great! So this grew, too.</p>

<h3 id="the-event">The Event</h3>

<p>The .NET Day takes place in Wallisellen at the Microsoft Office. It is focussing on the latest topics like Azure, the .NET Standard or ASP.NET Core and Angular.</p>

<p>You can see the website here <a href="http://dotnetday.ch/">.NET Day Switzerland</a>.</p>

<p>We only have one day, one track as we wanted to start small and see if the feedback is good. If so: Perhaps we will do this again! If the feedback is bad then we at least tried to do this and hopefully had a good day. We will analyse it and see what we can make better the mext time if there is a next time then.</p>

<h3 id="current-status">Current status</h3>

<p>Right now we are still searching for sponsors. The more sponsors we have the more we can do about merchandising such as shirts, lanyards etc. Focus is on paying the food for everyone. On the other side we “sold” all tickets. It is really sold out. I would have never thought that.</p>

<p>I think it is all prepared for a good day.</p>

<h3 id="things-to-say-more-important-than-anything-else">Things to say more important than anything else</h3>

<p>T H A N K S to everybody who was involved in this so far. Thank you Manuel, I could not have done this that far without you, thanks to all speakers and everyone I had to reject because the agenda was full, thank you for every retweet, for every email, every phone call! You are amazing. We will try to give everything back making this day a great great conference.</p>

<p>See you soon.</p>

<p>Fabian</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
